

Date of birth
28 June 1995
Adresse
Belouizdad, Algiers, Algeria
Phone
(+213) 541 701 322
Email
himda.mohammed@gmail.com
LinkedIn
linkedin.com/in/mohammedhimda

MOHAMMED HIMDA

DATA SCIENTIST

4+ years of broad-based experience coming up with data-driven solutions to solve various challenging problems using predictive modeling, data processing, data mining algorithms as well as data visualization. Possessing a strong math background, an extensive analytical skills and a significant ability to work in team environments.

Education

Master's degree in Actuarial science and Finance 2014 - 2019

National School of Statistics and Applied Economics / ENSSEA ex INPS – Algeria

Engineer in Statistics and Planning

2014 - 2019

National School of Statistics and Applied Economics / ENSSEA ex INPS – Algeria

Bachelor's degree in mathematics

2011 - 2014

El Amir Abdelkader High School - Algeria

Work Experience

Data Scientist 10-2021 – Today

Société Générale Algérie SGA, Algiers, Algeria / Risks Department

- Credit risk scoring
- IFRS 9 modeling (Probability of Default, Loss Given Default and the Exposure At Default)
- Building predictive models (Logistic regression, Time series forecasting, K-Means, Neural networks...)
- Back testing the predictive models
- Leading projects related to data within risks department
- Risk indicators calculation and analysis
- Building ETL and data mining algorithms
- Creating Power BI Dashboards (DAX / M)
- Member of AFMO Datalab created by the group Société Générale which aims to improve the quality of the data domain
- Prepare and conduct retail monitoring committees for group Société Générale AFMO
- Automate heavy and repetitive tasks within risks department

Principal Actuary

07-2021 to 09-2021

Compagnie Algérienne des Assurances CAAT, Algiers, Algeria / Risk Management Department

- Loss reserving estimation (Chain-Ladder, Bornhuetter-Ferguson...)
- Analyze and evaluate the existing pricing grid
- Insurance premium pricing using supervised learning methods
- Build interactive dashboards
- Create a risk assessment matrix
- Participate in the company's rating project by AM Best

Junior Actuary

12-2019 to 07-2021

Gulf Insurance Group Algeria gig Algeria, Algiers, Algeria / Entreprise Risk Management Department

- Loss reserving estimation using classical approaches (Chain-Ladder, Bornhuetter-Ferguson) as well as supervised learning methods
- Profitability indicators estimation (Loss Ratios, Combined Ratio...)
- Build a pricing grid based on generalized linear models
- Build predictive analytics
- Assessment of unearned premiums
- Data modeling and interactive dashboards building
- Prepare and present reports to gig Kuwait risk management unity
- Participate in the IFRS 17 international standard implementation project managed by Willis Towers Watson, PwC UK and gig Kuwait

Sales Analyst

01-2019 to 11-2019

Travel Agency, Algiers, Algeria

Part time

- Optimize the monthly number of organized flights as well as the allocated budgets
- Manage and analyze the agency's portfolio

Skills

Python

R

SQL

SAS

Power BI

DAX & M

Machine Learning

Deep Learning

Problem-solving

Languages

English

French



Hobbies & Interests

Basketball | Fitness | Coding for fun | Artificial Intelligence